翻译  小饭
翻译  珈美
翻译  痒痒惦记小跟班
翻译  江湖人称王姑娘
翻译  沫沫
翻译  丶Charl
翻译  杏仁斯嘉丽
时间轴  吉吉
后期  饿得慌
校对  草草
总监  草草
第四季  第十集
纸牌屋
人人影视倾情奉献
弗兰西斯·安德伍德
希瑟·邓巴
凯瑟琳·杜兰特
涉及到的超级代表
贝茨城
东
密苏里州  贝茨城
阿道希保留区
贝茨城葡萄园
不是
堪萨斯城
佩特罗夫:  杜兰特不是救市和约旦河谷事件中的关键人物
安东尼·莫雷蒂纪念基金
捐款
道格拉斯·斯坦普
谢谢您的5000美元捐款已收到
佩特罗夫:  杜兰特不是救市和约旦河谷事件中的关键人物
民主党全国代表大会
国务卿杜兰特
我们爱克莱尔
民主党全国代表大会
安德伍德夫妇获民主党提名
"她与佩特罗夫单独较量
"She squared off mano-a-mano with Petrov
敲定了救市协议
to finalize the bailout deal.
与此同时  杜兰特国务卿则无所事事地等候
Meanwhile, Secretary Durant twiddled her thumbs, waiting
连上谈判桌的资格都没有"
without a seat at the bargaining table."
很疯狂  对吧
Pretty wild, huh?
-什么时候发的  -凌晨三点
- When was that posted? -3:00 A.M.
你该走了
You should go.
-早餐都不给吗  -我要工作了
- No breakfast, even? - I have work to do.
欢迎回来  这是戏剧性的一天
Welcome back. It's a dramatic day.
我们看下现在情况
Let's see where things stand.
沃尔夫  可以看到形式大变
And, Wolf, you can see the big change.
凯瑟琳·杜兰特现在上了我们的总统提名墙
Catherine Durant now on our presidential nominating wall.
原本有望成为副总统的她
She has shifted from vice presidential hopeful
转而竞争总统候选人
to potential presidential candidate.
杜兰特成为候选人或许对那些对安德伍德
And a Durant candidacy might be appealing to Democrats
和邓巴都没兴趣的民主党人很有吸引力
who aren't enthusiastic about either Underwood or Dunbar.
设想一下
And imagine this scenario
纵观整个大会的大局
if we play this out through this convention.
希瑟·邓巴退出初选时支持率是46%
Heather Dunbar came out of the primaries, of course, with 46%.
这还不足以赢得提名
It's not enough to win the nomination,
但如果安德伍德总统要取胜
but for him to win, President Underwood,
他还需要这些超级代表
he still needs these superdelegates.
邓巴退出时他赢得了选民票
He won the popular vote when Dunbar withdrew,
但你的意思是他还没有取得绝对多数
but you're saying he doesn't have a technical majority.
659名超级代表尚未投票
659 superdelegates yet to weigh in,
所以弗兰克·安德伍德已经掉到了48%
so you see Frank Underwood drops down to 48%.
他依然领先  但还不足以获得提名
He's still in the lead, but not enough to clinch the nomination.
想听更复杂的吗  好像还不够复杂似的
And you want a little bit more intrigue, like we need that?
24个州  沃尔夫  标亮的这24个州
Twenty-four states, Wolf, these 24 states highlighted,
没有所谓的不忠代表法
they do not have so-called faithless delegate laws,
也就是说这24个州的代表没必要
meaning in these 24 states, the delegates don't have to,
法律上没有规定他们必须投票给
they are not legally bound to vote for the candidate
赢得本州初选或党团会议的候选人
who won their state's primary or caucus.
他们可以随心所欲投给任何人
They can vote for whoever they want.
他们可以投给希瑟·邓巴
They could vote for Heather Dunbar.
他们可以转投给凯瑟琳·杜兰特
They could switch over and vote for Catherine Durant.
沃尔夫  如果他们想的话  还可以投给你
Wolf, if they want, they could vote for you.
他们不会投给我的
So... They're not gonna vote for me.
但如果杜兰特国务卿吸走了足够的选票
But if Secretary Durant siphons off enough votes
或是安德伍德未能在初轮投票中获得多数
or Underwood doesn't get that majority in the first ballot,
那就一切皆有可能了吗
what, all bets are off?
我觉得今天唯一可以肯定的是
I think about the only sure bet today is
安德伍德总统一定恨不得
President Underwood must be wishing
当初没有同意召开开放党代会
he hadn't agreed to this open convention.
杜兰特或是邓巴真的有可能取胜吗
Does Durant or Dunbar really have a shot at winning this thing?
当然  现任总统本就不是获选上台的
Sure. You've got a president who wasn't elected to begin with.
他的健康状况现在也是一个大问号
His health is a giant question mark right now.
他这个任期非常艰难  再加上开放党代会
He's had a rocky tenure, plus you've got an open convention.
一切皆有可能
Anything could happen.
比如杜兰特成为劲敌
Like giving, uh, Durant a run for her money.
顺便提一下  头条网
Uh, Slugline, by the way,
转载了昨天政治新闻网的报道
picked up the Politico story from yesterday.
在选举现场可能会引起一定注意
It could get traction out there on the floor.
没错  而且在开放党代会上
That's true, and, again, at an open convention,
克莱尔·安德伍德也许会突然成为黑马
Claire Underwood may suddenly be the dark horse here.
母亲
Mother.
你好啊  克莱尔
Hello, Claire.
你怎么搬到楼下了
Why'd you move down here?
临终关怀的护士说我不该再上下楼梯了
Hospice lady said I shouldn't be going up and down stairs anymore.
而且我也喜欢这里  光线更充足
Besides, I like it. More light.
那是谁
Who's that?
汤姆  能让我们单独聊聊吗
Uh, Tom, would you give us a minute, please?
抱歉
Sorry.
不不  过来  小伙子
No, no. Come here, young man.
您好  黑尔太太
Hi, Mrs. Hale.
我叫汤姆
My name's Tom.
托马斯·耶茨  小说家  你应该听说过他
It's Thomas Yates, the novelist. You've probably heard of him.
我觉得从约翰·契弗起就没什么值得读的书了
I think everything since John Cheever isn't worth readin'.
您也许是对的
You're probably right.
克莱尔
Well, Claire...
你是来清点
did you come to take stock of
我死后你要继承的遗产吗
everything you're gonna inherit when I die?
很方便  不是吗
Well, it's convenient, isn't it,
有个濒死的母亲  可以拿来做出城的理由
having a dying mother when you need an excuse to skip town?
我们不会打扰你的
We won't disturb you.
认识您很高兴  黑尔太太
It was nice meeting you, Mrs. Hale.
-叫我伊丽莎白  -好  那您也叫我汤姆
- Elizabeth. - All right. Well, then you call me Tom.
我讨厌人叫我托马斯
I hate "Thomas."
-好  汤姆  -就这么说定了
- Fair enough, Tom. - We have a deal.
我们需要党内团结  而不是四分五裂
We want a unified party, not a fractured one.
我不能在规则上反复无常
I can't play fast and loose with the rules.
这是开放党代会  本就没有规则
This is an open convention. There are no rules.
我已经按你的意思把黄金时段给了希尔议员
I already gave Senator Sheer that prime-time spot that you wanted.
但这事  作为党代会主席
But this, as chair of the convention--
是我让你做党代会主席的
And I made you chair of this convention
就是想防备这种事
precisely for moments like this.
我有义务不徇私
I have an obligation to not play favorites.
你对党的义务
Your obligation to the party
就是对党领袖的义务
is an obligation to the leader of the party,
身为总统  我就是党领袖
and as the president, that would be me.
-没错吧  -是的  先生  但是
- Correct? - Yes, sir, but--
那这就无关徇私  而是党内团结
Then this isn't about favoritism. It's about solidarity.
我们已为您安排好车
We've got a car waiting to take you
带您去会场了  惠特克女士
to the convention hall, Ms. Whittaker.
我应民主党全国委员会
I call this convention to order
以及党代会主席  帕特·惠特克之命
of the Democratic National Committee
宣布会议开始
and the convention chair, Patti Whittaker.
早上好
Good morning.
我刚得知  总统要去华盛顿
I was just informed that the president will travel to Washington
会见国家安全小组
to meet with his national security team.
鉴于两项提名的主要竞争者
Given that key contenders for both slots on the ticket
今天都不能到场
aren't able to be on the floor today,
规则委员会建议
the Rules Committee has advised that
我们等他们回来
we should wait for their return
再进行下一轮投票
before any further votes are held.
现有一项动议  延期所有投票
There is a motion to postpone all votes
直到总统回来
until the president's return.
哈里发国已于昨晚深夜从苏瓦尔出发
ICO began its advance from As Suwar late last night,
据我们的计算和他们目前的行军速度来看
and by our calculations and their current pace,
我们预计他们会在72小时内到达幼发拉底河
we expect them to reach the Euphrates within 72 hours.
这可能影响公路和河道交通
Now, this could disrupt highway and river traffic,
但更重要的是
but more importantly,
这会使他们有机会
could give them the opportunity
破坏该地区的重要水坝
to destroy vital dams in the region.
因此  我现在就前往华盛顿
And as a result, I am heading to Washington right now
来讨论怎样阻止这次哈里发国的进军
so that we can decide exactly how we should stop this ICO advance.
这突然的计划变动
Is this sudden change of plans
是您昨天与康威州长会晤的结果吗
a result of your meeting with Governor Conway yesterday?
如果州长的言论促使哈里发国加速计划
Well, it wouldn't surprise me if ICO accelerated their plans,
我也不会惊奇
uh, because of the governor's comments.
他们懂得如何利用媒体的关注
They certainly know how to take advantage of media attention.
但无论事实是否如此
But whether that's the truth or not,
解决这个威胁迫在眉睫
this is an imminent threat which we must deal with immediately.
我很高兴总统听取我的意见
I'm glad the president heard me
并终于采纳了布洛哈特将军的建议
and finally took General Brockhart's advice to heart.
现在我们只能
Now we'll just have to
等着看看是否真能得到什么结果
wait and see if it actually results in anything.
只希望不会收效太小  太迟
I just hope it's not too little, too late.
州长先生  您现在如何打算  留在亚特兰大吗
What are your plans now, Governor? Remain in Atlanta?
不  我和汉娜要回到竞选活动中
No, Hannah and I are heading back on the trail.
我们在佐治亚州完成了我们要做的事
We accomplished what we needed to here in Georgia, and
我们今天要去亚利桑那州  然后去犹他州
we're heading off to Arizona today and then Utah.
总统先生  总统先生
Mr. President. Mr. President.
为什么去华盛顿  而不是在这里解决
Why Washington and not here?
这个问题太敏感  不能在外解决
This issue is too sensitive for a mobile White House.
我需要在战况室里
I need to be in the Situation Room
与行政人员和顾问团队一起讨论
with my entire staff and team of advisors around me.
总统先生  总统先生
Mr. President. Mr. President.
亚当
Yes, Adam.
总统先生  这是为了堵国务卿杜兰特的嘴吗
Mr. President, is this a way to silence Secretary Durant
因为路易斯安那州将她推入了总统竞选
after Louisiana put her in the running for president?
我不会把国家安全与政治竞争混为一谈
I don't use national security matters for political purposes.
你知道的  亚当
You know that, Adam.
如果你们还有其它问题  请向赛斯提问
You have any other further questions, please direct them to Seth.
非常感谢各位
Thank you all very much.
-要我一起去吗  -不  你留下
- You want me to come with? - No, you stay behind.
-掌控好局面  -是  先生
- Keep everything under control. - Yes, sir.
有消息称她已经离开亚特兰大了
There are reports that she's left Atlanta.
第一夫人是今早早些时候离开的
The First Lady left earlier this morning.
她母亲的健康状况在过去几天进一步恶化了
Her mother's health has deteriorated in the past few days.
亚当
Adam.
这是否意味着她会退出副总统的竞选
Does this mean she's out of the running for VP?
第一夫人从来就没参选过
The First Lady was never in the running.
她和总统会继续支持凯瑟琳·杜兰特
She and the president continue to support Catherine Durant--
四个孩子的父亲  水手
Father of four, sailor...
因为踩到了生锈的鱼钩导致葡萄球菌感染
staph infection from stepping on a rusty fish hook.
天呐
Heavens!
还有这个  嗯  你曾是只果蝇
And this one, yeah, you were a fruit fly.
-果蝇  -对
- A fruit fly. - Yes.
你曾是拉斯普京的伴侣  享用他14英寸的
You were a consort to Rasputin and his 14-inch...
俄帝国时期神棍
因为尺寸大而闻名
实为11英寸
不要  别说出来
No, don't say it.
我不用说  你已经在脑补了
I don't have to say it because you're already imagining it.
我看完了
I looked it over.
咱们出去谈
I'll meet you outside.
打算留给薇和那些姑娘们的
Uh, gonna leave all this to Vi and the girls
如果你不想要的话
if you're not interested.
外婆的首饰
Grandmother's jewelry?
要是我不至少跟你提一嘴
She'd turn over in her grave
她在墓里都得气得翻身
if I didn't at least offer it to you.
她品味真不错
She had great taste.
不然你以为我的品味从哪来的
Where do you think I got it from?
这是什么
What's this?
打开看看吧
Look at it. Open it up.
肯定还是值点钱的  第一夫人的乳牙
Must be worth somethin', baby teeth of the First Lady.
我挺喜欢那个小伙儿
I like that boy.
能逗我笑
Makes me laugh.
就像你父亲在世时那样
Like your father used to.
我想象不出爸爸扮成算命的是什么样
Can't imagine daddy dressed up as a fortune teller.
你会意想不到的  他也有逗逼的一面
Oh, you'd be surprised. He had a silly side to him.
我是没见过
Not that I ever saw.
有些事他只会在我面前做
Well, there were certain things that he only did with me.
你瞧  笑一笑能缓解疼痛
Oh, you see, laughter is good for the pain.
比吗啡还有效
Even better than this morphine.
-我来帮你吧  -不用  我自己能行
- Let me help you. - No, no, I can do it.
你走吧
You just go.
走
Go!
你把所有内容都划掉了
You crossed everything out.
-因为不够好  -我知道
- It wasn't good. - I know.
等她去世了  你打算对这里也那样吗
Is that what you're gonna do here, after she dies?
因为不够好  把一切都抹去
Cross everything out... because it wasn't good?
我不会和你谈论我母亲的
You're not going to get me to talk about my mother.
我希望不会
I hope not.
恨太丑恶了
Hatred's ugly.
天气这么好  不适合谈那个
It's too beautiful a day for that.
回去干活儿喽
Back to the salt mines.
请坐
Please, sit.
先生  这是哈里发国目前的位置
Sir, these are the current ICO positions.
我们还在起草任务项目
We're still drafting action items,
但是我们可给您一个大致的
but we can give you a rough sense--
在讨论军事选择之前
Well, before we discuss any military options,
我要和大马士革通话  看看他们能允许什么行动
I'd like to put a call in to Damascus and see what they'll allow.
国务卿女士  跟我一起来吧
Madam Secretary, won't you join me?
为了单独见我  你不惜召集
So you had to call a national security meeting
国家安全会议
just to get us in the same room?
也为了不让你和康威通话
And to keep you off the phone with Conway.
我只需要给他打一通电话  不需要第二通
All I needed was one call to him. I don't need to make another.
你不是真觉得他会任命你为国务卿吧
You don't actually think he's gonna make you Secretary of State, do you?
估计不会  但我真想看到
Probably not, but I would've paid good money
他告诉你消息时你的脸色
just to see your face when he told you.
我从没保证会和你一起参选
I never promised you the ticket.
我只说了会尽力
I promised you I'd try.
你是装作尽力
You pretended to try.
对克莱尔的支持不会凭空出现
Claire's support didn't just happen on its own,
你还好意思握着我的手
and you had the gall to take my hand,
看着我的眼睛  对我撒谎
look me in the eye and lie to my face.
-你错了  凯茜  -拜托  弗兰克
- You're mistaken, Cathy. - Oh, come on, Frank.
从沃克就职的那天起
I've had a front row seat to everything
我就近距离看到了一切
since the day Walker took office,
所有的谎言和背叛  我还帮了你
all the lies and betrayals, and I helped you.
我的错误是以为你不会在背后捅我一刀
My mistake was I assumed you wouldn't stab me in the back.
你的错误是弄巧成拙
Your mistake is that it backfired.
这完全是个人恩怨  对吧
This is all personal, isn't it?
完全是为了报复我在医院时  克莱尔那样对你
This is about how Claire treated you when I was in the hospital.
别这么小瞧我  这是生意
Give me more credit than that. This is business.
我们曾是合作伙伴  是你违约了
We were partners. You broke the contract.
-那你想要什么  -还有什么呢  弗兰克
- So, what do you want? - What else is there, Frank?
什么都没了
Nothing.
很简单  要么让克莱尔的票改投给我
It's simple. Either Claire's votes come my way...
要么我就把大会搞得一团乱
or I turn the convention upside down.
我们得谈谈赛斯
We need to talk about Seth.
我接到了许多前客户的电话
I've been getting calls from former clients.
你开口之前  我告诉你我干过的坏事吧
Now, before you say anything, here's the dirt.
我8年级时在一次数学测验上做过弊
I cheated on a math test in 8th grade,
我16岁时曾为返校节偷过一条裙子
I shoplifted a homecoming dress when I was 16,
我大一时跟一个女生联谊会的姐妹搞过
I experimented with a sorority sister in freshman year,
我2007年晚交了税
and I was late on my taxes in 2007.
但他不会找到任何开除我的正当理由
What he won't find is anything that justifies firing me.
他肯定只是在审查你  我们对每个人都要审查
I'm sure he was just vetting you. We do that with everyone.
你非要这样说的话  那好吧
Okay, if that's your story, then fine,
但我只在乎赢得大选
but all I care about is winning this election.
我们放下个人恩怨  团结合作  好吗
So let's get past our personal shit and be a team, okay?
我们在对抗同一个敌人  总统先生
We're fighting a common enemy here, Mr. President.
我们保持团结十分重要
It's important that we remain united.
嗯  我向你保证我们采取任何行动前
Yeah, and I can assure you that Secretary Durant will reach out
杜兰特国务卿都会跟你联系
before we conduct any operation.
非常感谢  总统先生
Thank you for your time, Mr. President.
我们一想出计划就会联系你
We'll be in touch as soon as we come up with a plan.
你一副我还能当国务卿的样子
You're acting like I'll still be Secretary of State.
如果你决策正确  就会是的
Well, if you play your cards right, you will be.
你还请过谁当你的副总统
Who else did you offer the VP slot to?
杰姬  奥斯汀  我  还有谁
There's Jackie, Austen, me. Anyone else?
奥斯汀自愿退出的  杰姬也是
Austen withdrew on his own, and so did Jackie.
我没有逼她退出
I did not push her out.
杰姬说你毫不尊重她
Jackie says you took her for granted,
说你威胁她  恐吓她
that you bullied her, you intimidated her.
她正在给加州的代表们
And that is what she is telling every member
一个一个打电话说这番话
of the California delegation, one phone call at a time.
加州  票很多
California. Lots of votes.
加州  民主党大会最大的票仓
California, the largest piece of delegates at the Democratic Convention.
我听说代表团正在倾向希瑟·邓巴
I'm told that delegation is trending toward Heather Dunbar.
来看一下  沃尔夫
Let's watch this, Wolf.
想像一下她只拿下
Let's imagine she only picked up
加州三分之二的代表
two-thirds of the California delegates.
这就超过300票了
That gets you above 300 there.
另外  我们估计她能守住她家乡康涅狄格州
Plus, we assume she'll keep her home state Connecticut's support.
这样起点就相当不错
Off to a pretty good start.
超过300张代表票  大概是7%的选票了
It's over 300 delegates. What, roughly, uh, 7% of the vote?
单单这些就足以使投票进入第二轮了吧
That alone could take this, what, to a second ballot?
没错  又是开放党代会
That takes it to a second ballot, an open convention again.
而且我们预计
Plus, we also assume that
路易斯安那州会继续支持凯瑟琳·杜兰特
Louisiana will stay with Catherine Durant.
至少在第一轮投票结束前
So, we are not going to have a definitive idea
我们无法确切估计
of how all this is gonna shape up
局势将如何走向
at least until they conduct the first ballot.
目前总统和杜兰特国务卿
There's still no update as to, uh,
将何时返回尚无新消息
when the president and Secretary Durant will return.
是啊  这也增加了不确定性
No, and that adds to some of the uncertainty here.
我们回到现场  看看情况如何
So let's go back to the floor, see how things are playing out.
文章里没有说明
It didn't specify in the article
当时车队是朝哪个方向开的
which direction the motorcade was heading.
朝东
East.
你确定吗
You're sure?
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
我去
Hot damn!
我保证你想当多久国务卿都可以
I am promising you Secretary of State for as long as you want it
你2024年竞选总统时我会全力支持
and my full support when you run for President in 2024.
谁知道呢  你说不好会走运
I mean, who knows, you might even get lucky.
我的肝脏或许在那之前就衰竭了
My liver might fail before then.
你把我的职位许给贝克的时候
Your promises stopped meaning much
你的承诺就没有意义了
after you promised Baker my job.
我完全没打算让他当国务卿
I have no intention of offering him Secretary of State.
那么你就像沃克骗你一样骗了他
Oh, so you lied to him the way Walker lied to you.
不  我和沃克又不是老交情
No. Walker and I didn't have a history.
沃克也不尊重我
And Walker didn't respect me.
你我是有交情的  凯茜  我也非常尊重你
You and I have a history, Cathy, and I respect you immensely.
但是我们共事才3年
But our history goes back three years.
克莱尔和我已经是30年的搭档了
Claire's and my partnership goes back 30.
你必须尊重这一点
You have to respect that.
我可能会...
I might have...
如果你一开始就对我说实话的话
if you had been honest with me from the beginning.
我也希望时间能倒退  可现在已经这样了
Well, I wish I could turn back time, but here we are.
你可以把我挡在亚特兰大之外  想多久多久
And you can keep me out of Atlanta for as long as you want,
但你不能永远拖着选票
but you can't hold the vote back forever.
时间在前进不是倒退  而时间站在我这边
Time's moving forward, not back. And time is on my side.
如果希瑟·邓巴想占总统不在的便宜
If Heather Dunbar wants to take advantage of the President's absence,
那是她的权利
that's her prerogative.
但是她仍在华府  也未发表公开声明
But she's still in D.C., there's no public statement.
你认为这是占便宜
You see that as taking advantage?
你认为如果不是她在华府幕后操纵
You think Congresswoman Sharp would make calls on her behalf
夏普议员会代表她打电话拉票吗
if she wasn't pulling the strings from Washington?
夏普说是她自己打的
Sharp says she's doing it on her own.
你没有任何证据表明她们有合作
You don't have any proof of coordination.
你说得对  我没有
You're right, I don't.
只是清楚人性  基本逻辑
Just human nature, basic logic,
而且比常人更了解
and a slightly better than average understanding
政治手腕
of political gamesmanship.
失陪一下  新闻发言人也要上厕所
Uh, if you will excuse me, even press secretaries have to pee.
-我马上回来  -好的
- I'll just be right back. - Okay.
失陪  抱歉  失陪
Excuse me. Excuse me. I'm sorry. Excuse me.
怎么了
What's up?
莉安知道了  我认为是你告诉了她
LeAnn knows, and I think you told her.
对  直截了当  我全告诉她了
I did. Straight up. I told her everything.
-走  上楼去  -不
- Let's go. Upstairs. - No.
-你说什么  -邓巴重回局内
- Excuse me? - You've got Dunbar in play,
杜兰特和总统在一起
you got Durant with the President,
第一夫人在达拉斯
and the First Lady's in Dallas.
这里的一屋子记者
And I've got a room full of press
我从早上八点就在努力应付他们
that I've been keeping at bay since 8:00 this morning,
等我把熊孩子都哄睡了
so I will tell you why I told her...
再跟你讲我为什么告诉她吧
after I tuck in all the children.
现在投票
Let's vote now!
请安静一下
Order, please!
现在请希尔参议员讲话
It is Senator Sheer's time to speak.
安静
Order!
也许我们应该遂凯茜的愿
Maybe we should let Cathy have her way.
如果现在投票  你们获胜  我们大选再战
If the vote's held now, you two win. We focus on the general.
为什么这么说
What's brought all this on?
我只是在想我们这么做
I just wonder if we're in over our heads,
是不是不自量力  弗兰西斯
Francis, trying to do this.
是因为你母亲吗
Is it your mother?
看到她病得这么重一定很不好受吧
I'm sure it's difficult to see her this sick.
她完全无助
She's completely helpless.
但我们并不无助  我们可以扭转局势
But we're not helpless. We can turn this around.
我想我只是...
I guess I'm just...
我不知道  也许我们做错了
I don't know, maybe... maybe we're making a mistake.
也许我还没准备好做你的竞选搭档
Maybe I'm not ready to be your running mate.
-康威有个四星将军  -你母亲快乐吗
- Conway has a four-star general. - Is she happy, your mother?
不  她很痛苦
No, she's miserable.
汤姆逗她笑  但大多数时候不快乐
Tom makes her laugh, but mostly, no.
想象一下我肝衰竭了
Imagine my liver's failing.
-想象我要死了  -弗兰西斯
- Imagine I'm dying. - Francis...
不  你就想象一下
No, I just want you to picture it for just a moment.
我躺在床上  像你母亲现在一样
There I am, lying in a bed just like your mother is now.
唯一能让我高兴的事
The only thing that would make me happy
就是知道我走了以后  你会接手
is to know that you would take over after I passed.
如果是凯茜
If it were Cathy...
我会和你母亲一样痛苦的
I'd be just as miserable as your mother is.
我会做好我的事
I'll do my part.
你就专注你的讲话
You just concentrate on that speech.
好  谢谢你  弗兰西斯
All right. Thank you, Francis.
晚安
Good night.
-她不吃东西吗  -她吞咽很困难
- She, uh... she won't eat? - It's hard for her to swallow.
你觉得她还有多少时间
How much time do you think she has?
我说不准  可能是几周
I can't be definitive, but... a couple of weeks, maybe.
如果她完全不进食  可能就只有几天了
If she stops eating altogether, it could be days.
她很痛苦
She's in a lot of pain.
她可以不用这么痛苦
She doesn't have to be.
到了这一步  我们可以让她舒适一些
When it gets to this point, we can make her comfortable.
舒适到让她的身体不再挣扎
Comfortable enough that the body will let go.
那是她想要的吗
Does she want that?
这个你该和你母亲讨论一下
That is something you should discuss with your mother.
我喜欢那些植物
I like the plants.
你放在那儿的那些
The plants you put in there.
小东西总能让人眼前一亮  对吧
It's the little things, right?
如果我们干掉精炼厂
If we take out the refineries,
就能切断他们的收入来源
that would eliminate their revenue stream.
没有了资源  他们就无法进军
They can't advance if they don't have the resources.
马克宗总统明确表示
President Makhzun made it very clear
不希望精炼厂被毁
he wants those to remain intact.
从战略角度看  那是我们最好的选择
It's our best option from a strategic point of view.
伤亡最小  对他们能力的冲击最大
Minimal loss of life, maximal impact on capability.
要么全面开战  要么就不打
It's either total war or nothing at all.
这可不符合外交策略  凯茜
Well, that doesn't sound very diplomatic, Cathy.
我们要和恐怖分子谈外交吗
We're going to be diplomatic with terrorists?
我向马克宗总统承诺过
I made a promise to President Makhzun.
你之前就违背过诺言  这次有什么不同
You've broken promises before. Why should this be any different?
不如我们休息一下  晚餐之后继续吧
Why don't we break for dinner? We'll pick this up afterwards.
我想再考虑一下
I wanna review this a bit more.
我会让人把食物送去罗斯福室
I'll have some food brought into the Roosevelt Room.
感谢各位
Thank you all very much.
凯茜  我们俩就在这里吃吧
Cathy, why don't you and I eat in here?
"要么全面开战  要么就不打"
"Total war or nothing at all"?
如果我在镜头前说
The moment I get in front of those cameras
康威是对的  布洛哈特也是对的
and I tell them that Conway is right and Brockhart is right,
你把哈里发国的事完全搞砸了
and that you completely bungled the ICO situation,
你觉得邓巴到时会怎么样
how do you think Dunbar will do then?
请送两份科布沙拉过来  谢谢
Can we get two Cobb salads in here, please?
-我不喜欢科布沙拉  -那你可以不吃
- I don't like Cobb salad. - Then you don't have to eat it.
谢谢你过来
Thanks for coming over.
我过来比你过去容易多了
Way easier coming here than you coming there.
我门外有十支新闻团队守着呢
Must be ten news crews outside of my house.
你怎么跑出来的
How'd you escape?
老办法  走后门
The old-fashioned way. Back door.
你怎么弄到我的住宅电话的
How did you get my home phone?
老办法
Oh, old-fashioned way.
《先驱报》的联络簿
Rolodex from the Herald.
-跟我来  不会很久的  -好
- Come with me. I won't keep you long. - Yeah.
-这些花了你多少时间  -几个月
- How long did this take you? - Couple of months.
我单独做的
I've been working on my own.
我们有一整队人手  都没发现这个
We had a whole team and we didn't find this.
你们或许没有深挖到贝茨城葡萄园
Well, you probably weren't digging as deep as the Bates City Vine.
没有
No.
我们把大部分精力放在追踪资金上了
We spent most of our energy tracking the money.
我们应该更关注出行记录的
We should've been more focused on the travel logs.
我是和一个披萨店的人聊了之后才想到的
I wouldn't have checked either until I spoke with a pizza guy.
后来我想到  他们有可能篡改出行记录
Then I realized they might be manipulating the logs.
于是你查到了拉尼根
Which gets you to Lanagin.
这还是不能证明他见了拉尼根
It still doesn't prove he met with Lanagin,
但我不知道车队还能去哪
but I don't know where else that motorcade would've been heading.
你打算把这个公开吗
Are you going public with this?
我是可以  但是他还能合理推诿
I could, but he has some plausible deniability.
全都推到密查姆身上
He pins it all on Meechum.
如果他掩盖了行踪
If he's covering up travel,
谁知道他还掩盖了什么
who knows what else he's covering up?
那才是我想要的报道
That's the story I want,
而不是什么特勤局人员修改记录
not some Secret Service man being loose with the books.
那你还没有引起注意
So you're still under the radar.
我得请你对这一切保密
I have to ask you to keep all this to yourself.
我知道你现在有了机会  这很诱人
I know it can be tempting now that... you have a chance,
但如果这一切过早公布  他会提高警惕
but if this goes public too early, his guard goes up.
我退出选举的时候很艰难
Listen, it was hard when I withdrew.
半数领导层和公众都抛弃了我
How the leadership abandoned me, how the public did.
花了些时间
It took some time...
但我看开了
but I made my peace.
我是赢是输本来就不好说
It's a crapshoot whether I can win this.
他可以反驳这样的报道
He can probably fight that off.
你得写一篇他无法反驳的报道
You need to write the story that he can't fight off.
你调查过他  突破点在哪里
You investigated him. Where's the weak link?
雷米·丹顿
Remy Danton.
那是汤姆弄的
Tom did that.
真遗憾  他会合适你的
It's a shame. He'd be good for you.
我从没相信过牙仙
I never believed in the tooth fairy.
但你还是把钱拿走了
Well, you took the money anyway.
能帮我把那盏灯关了吗  很刺眼
Could you turn off that light, please? Hurts my eyes.
你小时候  曾经
When you were small... you used to...
曾经求我  让黑暗停止
used to ask me to make it stop, the dark.
你还记得吗
Do you remember?
记得
Yes.
我向你保证我会的  早上就让它停
And I promised you I would... in the morning.
但该死的  你会每天晚上
But, damn it, you would sit at that window...
坐在窗前
every night...
想凭自己的力量让太阳升起来
trying to make the sun rise, all by yourself.
你脸靠在窗户上睡着后
Your daddy would put you in bed...
你爸爸会把你抱上床
after you'd fallen asleep with your face against the glass.
我那时非常嫉妒
And I was so jealous.
嫉妒我和爸爸吗
Of me and Daddy?
嫉妒你相信
That you believed.
你相信你可以让太阳升起
You believed you could make the sun rise.
我跟护士谈了  母亲
I spoke to her, Mother, the nurse.
我做不到
I can't do it.
我做不到  母亲
I can't do it, Mother.
我做不到你要我做的事
I can't do what you want me to do.
克莱尔
Claire...
你母亲去世
it'd help you win...
会帮你赢的
having your mother gone.
为我做这件事
Do this for me.
让我终于能
And let me be a help to you.
帮到你
Finally.
汤姆
Tom.
她想要你在场
She wants you to be there.
你想要什么呢
What do you want?
我也想要你在场
I want you to be there, too.
好了
Okay.
我告诉她是因为你让我别无选择
I told her because you put me in an impossible situation.
她没有把柄  但你就是不听
There's nothing on her, but you wouldn't listen.
那你来我家的时候肯定也没听进去
And you must not have listened when you came over to my house.
我说得很清楚
I was very clear.
那么  你又要把我丢到地上吗
So... you're gonna throw me on the ground again?
看  这里有杯子  来吧
Look, here's a glass. Let's go ahead.
你要把我炒掉吗
You wanna fire me?
好啊  不就是又有人辞职吗
Fine. It's another resignation.
继雷米  布洛哈特之后
After Remy, after Brockhart.
杜兰特和邓巴还虎视眈眈
With Durant, with Dunbar.
我是靠编故事谋生的
You know, I spin stories for a living.
我都形容不出这故事有多好拿来做文章
I can't begin to tell you how to spin this.
你开小冰箱可不是为了拿健怡可乐
You know, the minibar wasn't open because you wanted a Diet Coke.
我担心你  道格
I'm worried about you, Doug.
我不需要人担心
Nobody needs to worry about me.
你需要有人担心你
Yeah, somebody does...
因为这个焦土政策对我们很不好
because this scorched-earth policy is bad for us.
我才不在乎莉安·哈维  我们需要她
I don't give a rat's ass about LeAnn Harvey. We need her.
而你需要我  但我们都需要你
And you need me. And we both need you.
-处在最佳状态  -我很好
- At your best. - I'm fine.
是吗  你不让我控制损失
Are you? Instead of having me do damage control,
反而让我伤害自己人
you're having me do damage to one of our own.
我是在保护总统
I am trying to protect the president.
而我是在保护你
And I'm trying to protect you...
免受自己的伤害
from yourself.
你别瞎说了  你才不在乎我
You're so full of shit. You don't care about me.
你干了那种事  我本该恨你
After what you did, I should hate you.
但那样能给我们带来什么呢
But where does it get us?
看一下《电讯报》吧
Check out the Telegraph.
策略起效了
The strategy is working...
如果你肯的话
if you let it.
或者逼我辞职  你决定
Or make me resign. Your call.
-你还好吗  -那是她想要的
- Are you okay? - It's what she wanted.
我在问你
I was asking you.
把投票安排到明天
Schedule the vote for tomorrow.
我会飞回去在投票前讲话
I'll fly back to speak just before.
克莱尔  你母亲刚刚去世了
Claire, your mother just passed.
安排一下  弗兰西斯
Schedule it, Francis.
汤姆写了一篇讲稿  很不错
Tom wrote a speech. It's good.
-凯茜还没同意  -那就逼她同意
- Cathy's not on board yet. - Then get her on board.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
-我不是...  -不不  没关系
- I didn't mean to-- - No, no, it's all right.
我会搞定的
I'll get it done.
谢谢  明天见
Thank you. I'll see you tomorrow.
晚安
Good night.
让杜兰特国务卿去总统办公室见我
Ask Secretary Durant to meet me in the Oval.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
总统先生
Mr. President.
在咖啡桌上
Coffee table.
有趣的是我都没让他这么做
The funny thing is I didn't even have to ask him to do it.
他自己做的
He did it on his own.
我尤其喜欢他说
I especially like where he says,
"凯瑟琳·杜兰特堪用
"Catherine Durant is functional.
克莱尔·安德伍德强大"
Claire Underwood is formidable."
你看  时间没有站在你那边  而在我们这边
So, you see, you don't even have time on your side. It's on ours.
到明天早上  会有十几篇类似报道
By tomorrow morning, there'll be a dozen articles just like that.
所以你可以做选择
So you have a choice.
你可以选择在接下来四年中继续当国务卿
You can redeem yourself as Secretary of State
重树形象
over the next four years,
或选择被世人铭记为  在中东办砸了事
or go down in history as a fluke, who bungled the Middle East
在勃兰登堡谈不拢协议的没用货
and couldn't even close the deal in Brandenburg.
你有你的版本  我也有我的
You have your version. I have mine.
我相信我的版本会跟这个一样引人注目
I'm sure mine will get just as much traction as this.
但是我的版本会赢  因为这个报道更有意思
But my version wins because it's the better story...
并且事情也确实如此
and it's also exactly how things went down.
你看连真相都不向着你
You see, you don't even have the truth going for you.
我不怕你
I'm not scared of you.
我背书邓巴  会是一篇更好的报道
My endorsement of Dunbar, that makes for an even better story.
但你知道最棒的报道是什么吗
But you wanna know what the best story is?
克莱尔的母亲刚去世了
Claire's mother just died.
-我很遗憾  -我想你不是真心的
- I'm sorry to hear that. - Oh, I don't think you really are,
不过没关系  反正全世界除了你都会难过
but that doesn't matter because the rest of the world will.
等她明晚做完讲话
And by the time she gives her speech tomorrow night,
亚特兰大乃至全国的观众
there won't be a dry eye in Atlanta
都会为之动容落泪
or across the rest of the country.
你可以保住你的工作  凯茜
So, you get to keep your job, Cathy,
只要以你代表的票为交换
in return for your delegates.
这个提议依然有效
That offer is still on the table.
我一直很忠诚  我帮你得到了这个位置
I have been loyal. I got you that table.
你想继续守住  还是想拱手让给康威
Do you wanna keep it, or do you wanna give it to Conway?
我在等移植手术的时候
You know, when I was waiting for my transplant,
我产生了特别逼真的幻觉  你都不会相信
I had the most vivid hallucinations. You wouldn't believe 'em.
你知道我看到谁了吗
Do you know who I saw?
彼得·罗素和佐伊·巴恩斯  就在这个办公室里
Peter Russo and Zoe Barnes, right here in this room.
佐伊就在这张沙发上引诱我
Zoe was trying to seduce me, right here on this couch,
而彼得把我的脸按在这块玻璃上
and Peter, he shoved my face up against this glass.
香烟  剃须刀片和性爱
Cigarettes and razor blades and sex.
很可怕
It was terrifying.
我只想逃出这间
All I wanted to do was get out of this room
我费劲千辛万苦才进来的房间
that I worked so hard to get in.
但它们阴魂不散是有道理的
But of course, it makes sense that they would've haunted me
因为全都是真的
because it's all true.
-什么是真的  -卢卡斯·古德温所说的一切
- What is? - Everything Lucas Goodwin claimed.
我杀了他们两个  就像他说的那样
I killed them both, just like he said I did.
但当然没人会相信  永远不会有人相信
But of course, nobody believes it, and nobody ever will.
因为我们就是那么擅长
Because that's how good we are...
让东西
at making things...
消失
disappear.
不  我们没杀过人
No, we didn't kill anybody.
但如果需要
But we would have...
我们会的
if it was necessary.
你说得对  谈判该结束了
So, you're right, the time for negotiations is over.
你要交出你的代表
You will hand over your delegates,
继续在我的内阁任职
and you will serve on in my cabinet.
我们忘掉发生过的这一切
And we will forget that any of this ever happened.
因为如果你不照做
Because if you don't...
我向上帝发誓
I swear to God...
我永远
I will never...
都不会忘记
ever forget.
现在你明白了吗
Do you understand now?
明白
Yes.
好
Good.
我们去决定要怎么对付恐怖分子吧
Now, let's go decide what we're gonna do about these terrorists.
需要我给谁打电话吗  做些安排
Want me to call someone? Make arrangements?
我们让太阳升起来了
We made the sun rise.
这她也告诉你了
She told you that, too?
我们该动身了
We should get going.
我和汉娜想向第一夫人和总统
Me and Hannah want to extend our warmest condolences
致以最诚挚的哀悼
to the First Lady and the President.
我们为他们和伊丽莎白·黑尔的亲人们祈祷
They and all of Elizabeth Hale's loved ones are in our prayers.
出于对离世之人的尊敬  今天我们不竞选
And we won't be campaigning today out of respect for their loss.
愿上帝保佑总统夫妇
God bless President and Mrs. Underwood.
好了
Got it.
发布吧
Put it out.
她倒毙的时机掐得真好
Perfect timing... for her to drop dead.
我们本来正顺风顺水呢
We were on a roll, too.
我该准备讲话了
I should prep for the speech.
我为你准备好了房间  我马上就过去
I have a room set up for you. I'll be right in.
这边请  安德伍德夫人
Right this way, Mrs. Underwood.
我读过草稿了
I read the draft.
怎么样
And?
-一个字都不用改  -我很高兴你满意
- I wouldn't change a thing. - I'm glad you're pleased.
我很高兴你陪着她
I'm glad you were with her.
她很坚强  你很幸运
She's strong. You're a lucky man.
完全同意
Don't I know it.
女士们先生们  我很荣幸为大家介绍
Ladies and gentlemen, it is a great honor to introduce
国务卿凯瑟琳·杜兰特
Secretary of State Catherine Durant.
谢谢  非常感谢大家
Thank you, thank you very much.
我知道大家和我一样
I know that all of you join me
都对第一夫人亲人的离世表示诚挚慰唁
in offering our sincere condolences to the First Lady for her loss.
今晚  我想向在代表大会上
Tonight, I want to offer my sincere gratitude
支持我的各位代表
to all the delegates who have honored me with their support
致以我最真挚的感谢
during the course of this convention.
我非常感谢你们
Thank you so much.
然而  经过深思熟虑
However, after much deliberation...
我决定  与辞职参加选举相比  作为国务卿
I have decided that I have more to offer you as Secretary of State
我能更好地为大家服务
than to resign and run for office.
但我希望支持我的各位
But I want to encourage every one of you who has supported me
和我一起支持这位非凡的女性
to join me in supporting this extraordinary woman,
美国第一夫人  克莱尔·黑尔·安德伍德
the First Lady of the United States, Claire Hale Underwood.
谢谢
Thank you.
晚上好
And good evening.
正如大家所知  我母亲
As all of you know, my mother,
伊丽莎白·康斯坦斯·黑尔
Elizabeth Constance Hale,
久病后于昨晚去世
passed away last night after a long illness.
她是个坚强的女人...
She was a strong woman...
一个生猛的德州人
a fierce Texan...
从小...我和她关系就不好
We had... a difficult relationship from childhood onwards.
我们曾有过很长时间的疏离
At times, there were long periods of estrangement.
我们经常深深地伤害对方
We hurt each other... often and deeply.
如果说母亲的病带来了什么好事  那就是
If there was one good thing that came from my mother's illness...
让我们有机会重新开始往来  抚平旧伤
it gave us a chance to reconnect, to mend old wounds.
人们并不是都能
And that's not an opportunity
在父母离世前有这样的机会
people always get before a parent dies,
我很感激有这样的机会
and I'm grateful to have had that.
那我在这里做什么呢
And what am I doing here?
我站在这里  是因为这是我母亲所希望的
I'm here because my mother wanted me to be.
昨天在她去世之前  她对我说
Yesterday, before she passed, she said to me,
"克莱尔...去做吧
"Claire... do this.
如果这是人们希望的  听他们的
If the people want it, listen to them.
如果失败了  那就是失败了
And if you lose, then you lose.
但是如果你赢了...
But if you win...
要感到荣幸  保持谦逊
be honored, be humbled,
和弗兰西斯一起赢得选举"
and win this election with Francis!"
我告诉她  康威夫妇是非常厉害的对手
And I told her, I said, "The Conways are tough opponents."
她说也许是吧  但也不比德州人
And she said, "They may be tough, but they're not Texas tough."
失去让我们深思
Loss is a sobering phenomenon.
几个月前  我差点失去了我丈夫
Several months ago, I almost lost my husband.
我们的国家差点失去了总统
Our nation almost lost a President.
失去让我们重新审视我们珍惜的一切
Loss makes us reevaluate what we hold dear.
我还要告诉你们...
And I'll tell you, there were...
就在不久之前
times in the not too distant past,
弗兰西斯和我...差点失去我们的婚姻
where Francis and I, we... almost lost our marriage.
我们遇到了困难  还以为坚持不下去了
Hard times when we thought we wouldn't make it.
正如很多人所知
And like many of you know,
婚姻并非总是一帆风顺
marriage isn't always the smoothest road.
是一个精神错乱的年轻人
And it took the actions of a deranged young man
让我记起弗兰西斯对我有多重要
to remind me how important Francis is to me.
现在  我母亲去世了...
And now, with my mother gone...
他就是我唯一的亲人了
he's the only family I have left.
我愿把我的人生  我们的国家和未来
I trust Francis Underwood with my life,
托付给弗兰西斯·安德伍德
with our nation, with our future.
我希望你们也能信任他
I hope you will, too.
如果你们信任我们  我会谨遵母亲的话
And if you trust the both of us, I'll heed my mother's words,
如被提名为他的竞选搭档  我将深感荣幸
and I'll be honored if you nominate me as his running mate.
克莱尔  克莱尔  克莱尔
Claire! Claire! Claire!
天呐  你真厉害
Jesus! You did great work.
女士们先生们...
Ladies and gentlemen...
秘书长女士  作为党代会主席
Madam Secretary, as Convention Chair,
我提议通过口头表决  对提名
I move that we make the nomination
克莱尔·安德伍德竞选副总统
of Claire Underwood for Vice President...
弗兰西斯·安德伍德竞选总统做出表决
and Francis Underwood for President by acclamation.
对总统和副总统的提名
Do I hear a second to vote by acclamation
进行口头表决  是否有人附议
for the nomination of the President and the Vice President?
-说得好  -提议通过
- Hear, hear! - So moved.
赞成提名
All of those in favor of the nomination
弗兰斯西·安德伍德
of Francis Underwood for
竞选美国总统的说赞成
President of the United States, say "Aye."
-赞成  -反对提名的
- Aye! - All those against.
反对
Nay!
赞成提名克莱尔·安德伍德
All those in favor of the nomination of Claire Underwood
竞选美国副总统的说赞成
for our Vice President of the United States, say "Aye."
赞成
Aye!
-反对提名的  -反对
- Against? - Nay!
赞成者占多数
The Ayes have it!
本党决定2016年总统选举候选人
Our party's ticket for the 2016 Presidential Election
为弗兰西斯和克莱尔·安德伍德
will be Francis and Claire Underwood!